ABOUT

I'm an Integrations Specialist / Full Stack Application Developer with experience working as a UI, UX, & QA engineer, system administrator. Current career goals & objectives include designing and implementing enterprise-scale systems, minimizing costs & maximizing performance of software solutions, improving operational efficiency of organizations, learning new technologies to overcome business challenges. Other professional interests include analytics, data science, fintech / investing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Babson College

Integrations Specialist

Babson Park, MA Jul 2019 – present

- I write integrations for a variety of systems using SOAP and RESTful web services, APIs, ETL tools, MS SQL Server.
- I work with and help configure Salesforce.com (Sales/HEDA Cloud), Informatica (ICS, DI, APIs), Workday (HCM, Finance, Student), JIRA (on prem), Cvent, SharePoint, Canvas, Blackboard, EMS, Neoload, and other technologies.

Application Developer

Apr 2014 - Jul 2019

- Designed, developed, and maintained complex, dynamic, enterprise-level web applications using Adobe ColdFusion/Fusebox, Java, PHP/Drupal, C#/.NET, JS, CSS.
- Wrote custom two-way web services and data feeds to integrate internal data stores and systems with a variety of third party applications and tools.

Software Developer Co-op / Application Developer Intern

May 2012 - Apr 2014

- Created and maintained dynamic web applications for the Babson Portal a platform of over 150 custom written tools with 2,000,000+ lines of code; researched, proposed, and integrated new software solutions.
- Developed custom system workflows (XML), services, and events (JellyScript) in JIRA, performed system administration of the Atlassian stack (JIRA, Confluence) including data back-up, indexing, and restoring, system troubleshooting, patching, etc.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced knowledge of Adobe ColdFusion, t-SQL, JavaScript, CSS, XML/HTML, ETL tools (Informatica, SSIS), SOAP and RESTful web services, JIRA, Confluence.

Intermediate knowledge of C/C#, .NET, Java, PHP, Drupal, Force.com platform, SOQL/APEX/Visualforce, Workbench, git, VSS, Workday, Cvent, and Canvas APIs.

Familiarity with Assembly (MASM), Python, Perl, Objective C/Swift, most flavors of shell scripting, SharePoint, Selenium, CrazyEgg, Mendix, Neoload, Laserfiche, webRTC, webVR, MEAN stack.

EDUCATION

Babson College

Babson Park, MA

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business

Sep 2018 – Dec 2019

Master of Science in Business Analytics

- BI&A consulting project for a customer of an ERP software company with the project goal of developing statistical models to highlight the effects of local weather on store traffic.

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business

May 2016 – Aug 2018

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business Analytics concentration

- BI&A management consulting project for a local celebrity owned fast-casual burger chain with the project goal of identifying key loyalty, satisfaction, and traffic drivers for its customer base.

Wentworth Institute of Technology

Boston, MA

College of Engineering and Technology
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sep 2011 – <u>Apr 2014</u> GPA: 3.82

- Dean's List (2011-2014), graduated with honors: magna cum laude
- Tau Alpha Pi Honor Society, Applied Math minor, 2014 Annual Awards Recipient
- Wentworth Community Scholarship and Wentworth Merit Scholarship Recipient

University of Tyumen (transferred out)

Tyumen, Russia

Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science

Sep 2008 – May 2011

BS/MS in Software Development and Information Systems Administration

- Full Tuition Scholarship
- Outstanding Incoming Class Award Recipient

CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, SEMINARS, AND HACKATHONS

- Red Hat Security Symposium, Dec 2019 (Waltham, MA)
- Eliassen Group Agile Foundations 2-day onsite training, May 2019 (Wellesley, MA)
- The Citizens Challenge FinTech Hackathon, Jul 2018 (Boston, MA)
- Babson Finance Conference, Mar 2018 (Boston, MA)
- TERMINALFOUR Advanced Web Developer, 3-day onsite training, Jan 2018 (Wellesley, MA)
- Reality Virtually Hack @ MIT, Oct 2017 (Cambridge, MA) Project: WebVR Checkout
- Programmatic Development Using Apex and Visualforce (DEV450), Sep 2017 (Boston, MA)
- Hacking for Good @ HBS, Jun 2017 (Boston, MA)
- InformaticaWorld, May 2017 (San Francisco, CA)
- HackWITus @ WIT, Mar 2017 (Boston, MA) Project: WebArm
- AT&T WebRTC Boston Coding Workshop, May 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Future of Wearables Scramble™ @ Babson, Apr 2016 (Wellesley, MA)
- Salesforce World Tour, Apr 2016, May 2017, Apr 2018 (Boston, MA)
- Boston Code Camps (24 27), Nov 2015, 2016 & Mar 2016, 2017 (Cambridge, MA)
- Workday Higher Education Summit, Oct 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2015 (Manchester, NH) Project: Conversion Wars Web App
- NeoLoad 3-day training, Feb 2015 (Waltham, MA)
- <u>Laserfiche</u> 4-day training, Sep 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Mendix 3-day onsite training, Aug 2014
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2014 (Manchester, NH) Project: <u>DWC Boy Scouts iOS App</u>

VOLUNTEER SERVICE AND ACTIVITIES

CommonWealth Kitchen

- Non-voting member of the board, Babson Board Fellow (2018-2019 cohort)

Babson

- Advanced Degree Employee Resource Group (ERG) Chair
- Analytics and Race Conversations ERGs member
- Community Learning Day (CLD) Committee Member
- Entrepreneurial Thought & Action (ET&A) Award Selection Committee Member
- "Kids on Campus Day" Garden Session Volunteer
- Commencement Volunteer

Wentworth

- Admissions Blogger, Admissions Office
- Web Application Developer, Career Services
- International Student Ambassador, International Student Services
- President's Host, **President's Host Society**
 - Represented the Institute at various events, on and off campus
 - o Served as an ambassador of public relations in various supporting roles
 - o Promoted Wentworth's academic programs, services and student activities
- Alternative Spring Break Volunteer, Community Partnership Office
 - Focused on environmental work in the Biscayne and the Everglades National Parks, FL
 - Worked with wounded birds at the Florida Keys Wild Bird Sanctuary, FL
 - Worked with animals at Florida Monkey Forest Zoo, Key Largo, FL
- Note Taker for a Disabled Student, Counseling Center & Disability Services Partnership

AFFILIATIONS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

- I sat on the board of <u>CommonWealth Kitchen</u> as a Babson Board Fellow during 2018-2019.
- I've been a member of TAΠ (<u>Tau Alpha Pi</u>, Massachusetts Alpha Chapter) the professional honor society for engineering technology since 2013.
- Occasionally, I participate in the local Boston technology meetups, hackathons, and user group activities such as BNT (Boston New Technology), <u>Boston AUG</u> (Atlassian User Group), <u>Code</u> <u>for Boston</u> Hack Nights, and others.
- I am a frequent <u>Kiva.org</u> lender and encourage you to become one.
- Outside of my day-to-day duties as a developer I enjoy cycling, <u>creating</u> and <u>playing</u> music, learning new things, and generally expanding my horizons.